为阻止动荡局势进一步恶化
"In order to affect a timely halt to deteriorating conditions.
为了百姓大众的利益
and to ensure the common good,
该地处于警戒状态
a state of emergency is declared for these territories.
贝克特勋爵
by decree of Lord Cutler Beckett,
被皇帝陛下委派至此
duly appointed representative of His Majesty, the king.
根据宵禁法
By decree, according to martial law,
对以下法规做出暂时修订
the following statutes are temporarily amended:
公共聚众权 被剥夺
Right to assembly, suspended.
人身保护权 被剥夺
Right to habeas corpus, suspended.
法律咨询权 被剥夺
Right to legal counsel, suspended.
陪审团议罪权 被剥夺
Right to verdict by a jury of peers, suspended.
法令规定 凡定罪为海盗者
By decree, all persons found guilty of piracy,
协助海盗者
or aiding a person convicted of piracy,
与海盗有瓜葛者
or associating with a person convicted of piracy…
将处以绞刑
…shall be sentenced to hang by the neck until dead."
∮ 皇帝和他的仆人 ∮
∮ The king and his men ∮
∮ 虏走皇后 ∮
∮ Stole the queen from her bed ∮
∮ 将她封印在肉体中 ∮
∮ And bound her in her bones ∮
∮ 大海为我们所拥有 ∮
∮ T he seas be ours ∮
∮ 拥有无限力量 ∮
∮ And by the powers ∮ ∮
∮ 随心所欲 四处漂流 ∮
∮ Where we will, we'll roam ∮
∮ 呦吼 ∮
∮ Yo ho ∮
∮ 千万双手 ∮
∮ All hands ∮
∮ 把帆高挂 ∮
∮ Hoist the colors high ∮
∮ 拒绝 ∮
∮ Heave-ho ∮
∮ 小偷乞丐 ∮
∮ Thieves and beggars ∮
∮ 我们永垂不朽 ∮
∮ Never shall we die ∮
∮ 呦吼 ∮
∮ Yo ho ∮
∮ 齐心协力 ∮
∮ Haul together ∮
∮ 把帆高挂 ∮
∮ Hoist the colors high ∮
贝克特勋爵
Lord Beckett!
他们开唱了 长官
They've started to sing, sir.
- 很好 - ∮ 小偷乞丐 ∮
- Finally. - ∮ Thieves and beggars ∮
∮ 我们永垂不朽 ∮
∮ Never shall we die ∮
《加勒比海盗3：世界的尽头》
∮ 有人死去 有人活着 ∮
∮ Some have died and some are alive ∮
∮ 有人在海上航行 ∮
∮ Others sail on the sea ∮
∮ 带上牢笼的钥匙 ∮
∮ With the keys to the cage ∮
∮ 以及严重的后果 ∮
∮ And the devil to pay ∮
∮ 我们努力前往费德勒绿地（水手们想象中的天堂） ∮
∮ We lay to Fiddler's Green ∮
∮ 水之坟墓中升起一口钟 ∮
∮ The bell has been raised from its watery grave ∮
∮ 发出阴沉的声音 ∮
∮ Hear its sepulchral tone ∮
∮ 警告所有人 注意暴风雪 ∮
∮ A call to all Pay heed the squall ∮
∮ 转动船帆回家 ∮
∮ Turn your sails to home ∮
∮ 呦吼 ∮
∮ Yo ho ∮
∮ 齐心协力 ∮
∮ Haul together ∮
∮ 把帆高挂 ∮
∮ Hoist the colors high ∮
∮ 拒绝 ∮
∮ Heave-ho ∮
小偷乞丐
Thief and beggar.
∮ 我们永垂不朽 ∮
∮ Never shall we die ∮
唱这歌可是要杀头的
A dangerous song to be singing…
即使不懂背后的含义
…for any who are ignorant of its meaning.
尤其是个女孩子家
Particularly a woman.
尤其是孤身一人的女孩子家
Particularly a woman alone.
你凭什么认为她孤身一人？
What makes you think she's alone?
你罩着她？
You protect her?
你凭什么认为我需要别人罩着？
And what makes you think I need protecting?
你家老大正等着我们
Your master's expecting us.
死人会耽误时间
And an unexpected death'd cast a slight pall on our meeting.
步伐整齐
Pick those feet up!
跑步前进
On the double!
朝前看
Eyes front!
不 不 不 没有
No, no, no. None.
要花上一个星期后 我才不会晕船
lt always takes me about a week to get my sea legs.
上一次 我呕吐得很厉害
I was throwing up horribly the last time.
像她那样稳着些
Steady as she goes.
好的
All right.
有威尔的消息吗？
Have you heard anything from Will?
特纳一定会取得航海图的
I trust young Turner to acquire the charts.
在邵峰船长面前不要没大没小
and you to remember your place in the presence of Captain Sao Feng.
他真有那么可怕吗？
Is he that terrifying?
他性情很像我 但心狠手辣 且唯利是图
He's much like myself, but absent my merciful nature and sense of fair play.
准备通过 准备好
We're through. Make ready.
快点
Hurry now.
你是不是认为 她是个女人 就不会怀疑到她了？
Do you think because she is a woman we would not suspect her of treachery?
既然你这么说…
Well, when you put it that way…
脱下来
Remove. Please.
脱
巴布萨船长 欢迎来到新加坡
Captain Barbossa, welcome to Singapore.
加蒸汽
More steam.
没门儿
None of that.
如果他们不成功 那我们就是唯一的希望了
If things don't go the way we want, then we're the only chance they've got.
我听说你有事相求
I understand that you have a request to make of me.
应该说是项提议
More of a proposal to put to ye.
我有趟探险 需要一条船 一队人
I've a venture underway and I find myself in need of a ship and a crew.
真是巧…
Hmm. It's an odd coincidence.
你是不是有一条闲船 一队闲人？
Because you happen to have a ship and a crew you don't need?
不是说这个
No.
因为今天早前 附近不远
Because earlier this day, not far from here,
一个毛贼潜入我叔叔的庙里
a thief broke into my most revered uncle's temple.
企图偷走
and tried to make off with these.
航海图
The navigational charts.
上面有去世界尽头的路线
The route to the Farthest Gate.
进入另一个世界探险
Wouldrt it be amazing if this venture of yours.
会不会很精彩呢？
took you to the world beyond this one?
这纯属巧合 不要胡乱猜测
Lt would strain credulity at that.
就是这个毛贼 面熟吗？
This is the thief. Is his face familiar to you?
留他还有何用？
Then I guess he has no further need for it.
不 不
No, no!
你到了我的地盘 却辜负了我的盛情
You come into my city and you betray my hospitality.
- 我向你保证 我不知情 - 你是不知道他会失手吧
- I assure you I had no idea… - That he would get caught!
你们企图前往戴维·琼斯的魔狱
You intend to attempt the voyage to Davy Jones' Locker.
我实在想不通
But I cannot help but wonder…
为什么？
Why?
起义歌已经被传唱 刻不容缓啊
The song has been sung. The time is upon us.
我们必须召集天下海盗王大会
We must convene the Brethren Court.
做为九大海盗王之一的你 有责任遵守誓约出席大会
As one of the nine pirate lords, you must honor the call.
加蒸汽
More steam.
More steam!
- 我们人人头上都有悬赏 - 嗯
- There is a price on all our heads. - Aye.
是的
It is true.
这年头海盗也只能靠
It seems the only way a pirate can turn a profit anymore…
出卖其他海盗牟利
…is by betraying other pirates.
我们现在应该求同存异
We must put our differences aside.
等信号
Wait for the signal.
海盗王大会制定了海洋公约
The First Brethren Court gave us rule of the seas.
贝克特勋爵却让这公约失去了效用
But now that rule is being challenged by Lord Cutler Beckett.
面对东印度公司
Against East India Trading Company,
海盗公会哪有招架之力？
what value is the Brethren Court?
你我又能做些什么？
What can any of us do?
你可以打仗 放开我
You can fight! Get off me!
你是邵峰啊 新加坡大名鼎鼎的海盗王
You are Sao Feng, the pirate lord of Singapore.
你领导了一个时代 勇敢的船长可以自由遨游
You command in an age of piracy where bold captains sail free waters.
见过的大浪非尺能量
Where waves aren't measured in feet, but as increments of fear,
经过检验的人都成了传奇
and those who pass the test become legend.
你能眼睁睁地看着这一切 都毁在你的手中么
Would you have that era come to an end on your watch?
遍天下的海盗王
The most notorious pirates from around the world.
都在团结备战
are uniting against our enemy,
你竟然还躲在洗澡水里
and yet you sit here cowering in your bathwater!
伊丽莎白·斯旺
Elizabeth Swann.
不要妄下评论
There is more to you than meets the eye, isn't there?
你不够格
And the eye does not go wanting.
不过我注意到 你们还没回答我的问题
But I cannot help but notice you have failed to answer my question.
找戴维·琼斯的魔狱目的何在？
What is it you seek in Davy Jones' Locker?
为了杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
他是海盗王之一
He's one of the pirate lords.
我让斯派洛重返人世
The only reason…
唯一的理由…
…I would want Jack Sparrow returned from the land of the dead…
就是好亲手把他再送回魔狱
…is so I can send him back myself!
九枚西班牙古银币 杰克·斯派洛手上有一枚
Jack Sparrow holds one of the nine pieces of eight.
死前没来得及传给继承人
He failed to pass it along to a successor before he died.
我们必须把他救回来
So we must go and get him back.
这也就是说
So you admit…
你现在承认欺骗了我
…you have deceived me.
操家伙
Weapons!
Weapons.
邵峰 我发誓我们的初衷是好的
Sao Feng, I assure you, our intentions are strictly honorable.
放下武器 不然就杀了他
Drop your weapons or I kill the man!
杀吧 反正不是我们的人
Kill him. He's not our man.
如果不是你的人 那就不是我们的人
If he's not with you, and he's not with us…
他是谁的人呢？
…who's he with?
装弹药
Charge!
威尔！
Will!
注意你的后面
Look out! Look behind you!
预备
Ready!
开火
Fire.
航海图
Chart!
不
Boo!
整队 准备 开火
Company! Make ready. Set. Fire!
整队
Company!
准备 开火
Make ready. Set.
开火
Fire!
真是巧 不是吗？
Lt's an odd coincidence, isn't it?
你刚到新加坡 东印度公司就找到我的头上
The East India Trading Company finds me the day you show up in Singapore.
纯属巧合
It is coincidence only.
如果你想和贝克特交易 就需要我帮你
Lf you want to make a deal with Beckett, you need what I offer.
你已经背叛了巴布萨 现在还要背叛斯派洛
You cross Barbossa. You are willing to cross Jack Sparrow.
我凭什么信任你？
Why should I expect any better?
我需要黑珍珠号救回我父亲
I need the Black Pearl to free my father.
你可以帮我夺得黑珍珠号
You're helping me to get it.
爬下
Fire in the hole.
多谢 杰克
Thank you, Jack.
- 得到航海图了吗？- 不仅如此
- You have the charts? - And better yet.
- 一条船 一队人 - 邵峰哪去了？
- A ship and a crew. - Where's Sao Feng?
他会保护我们脱身 然后在沉船湾和我们会面
He'll cover our escape and meet us at Shipwreck Cove.
这边 快
This way. Be quick.
尽力绑紧
Haul the snotters with a will!
绑紧了
Keep it taut.
注意安全 装载货物
Secure provisions and stow the cargo.
邵峰现已无藏身之处
There's no place left for Sao Feng to cower.
他会遵守誓约吗？
Do you think he will honor the call?
很难说
I cannot say.
海上的凶神恶煞
There's an evil on these seas.
就算嗜血海盗也会畏惧三分
that even the most staunch and bloodthirsty pirates have come to fear.
西班牙古银币
A piece of eight.
你说 有9件的
Nine of them, you say.
我们新加坡的新朋友很特别 先生
Our new friend in Singapore was very specific, sir.
九枚西班牙古银币
Nine pieces of eight.
背后有什么含义呢？
What's the significance of that, I wonder.
我们的舰队所向披靡
Nothing can hold against the armada.
就算是「飞翔的荷兰人号」也不是对手
Not with the Flying Dutchman at the lead.
我们一无所知
Nothing we know of.
你那个朋友提到海盗公会 将在哪里开会吗？
Did your friend mention where the Brethren Court are meeting?
他支支吾吾的
He was mum on that, sir.
嗯
Hmm.
他懂得消息的价值
Then he knows the value of information.
这些话不要对外人透漏
Better keep this between ourselves.
免得某些人趁机逃到新加坡去
We don't want anyone running off to Singapore, do we?
- 嗯 司令官 - 您找我 贝克特勋爵？
- Ah, admiral. - You summoned me, Lord Beckett.
没错 有件东西给你
Yes. Something for you there.
新官上任 找位老战友协助你
Your new station deserves an old friend.
- 没有征用令了吧？- 没了 长官
- Not more requisition orders. - No, sir.
只剩下死刑令
Execution.
海盗公会知道他们面临灭顶之灾
The Brethren know they face extinction.
他们唯一可选的是去哪里做殊死一搏
All that remains is for them to decide where they make their final stand.
没人说过会这么冷啊
No one said anything about cold.
苦尽则甘来
I'm sure there must be a good reason for our suffering.
那个臭女人怎么不把杰克
Why don't that obeah woman bring Jack back the same way.
- 像巴布萨那样也带回来？- 因为巴布萨只是死了
- she brought back Barbossa? - Because Barbossa was only dead.
而杰克·斯派洛的躯体和魂魄
Jack Sparrow is taken, body and soul,
并非被囚禁在死亡地带 而是在惩罚地带
to a place not of death, but punishment.
一个人最悲惨的命运莫过于此
The worst fate a person can bring upon himself…
只能无奈的面对永久
…stretching on forever.
这就是戴维·琼斯的魔狱
That's what awaits at Davy Jones' Locker.
是的 我就知道有原因
Yeah. I knew there was a good reason.
没有标识吗？
Nothing here is set.
这可没有现代航海图精确
These can't be as accurate as modern charts.
是啊 但它可以带我们去很多地方
No. But it leads to more places.
「越过边缘」
"Over the edge.
「再来一次」
Over again."
日出时会释放
"Sunrise sets.
「绿灿烂」
Flash of green."
来给大家解释一下吧 巴布萨船长？
Do you care to interpret, Captain Barbossa?
目睹过「绿灿烂」吗？吉布斯
Ever gazed upon the green flash, Master Gibbs?
我有幸目睹过 极为罕见
I reckon I seen my fair share. Happens on rare occasion.
日落前的一霎那 绿灿烂直冲云霄
The last glimpse of sunset, a green flash shoots up into the sky.
有些人终其一生也无法看到
Some go their whole lives without ever seeing it.
有些人谎称见过
Some claim to have seen it who ain't. And some say…
这意味着一个灵魂重返人间
It signals when a soul comes back to this world from the dead.
- 对不起 - 相信我 小特纳
- Sorry. - Trust me, young Master Turner.
去死亡之地并不难
It's not getting to the land of the dead that's the problem.
如何返回才是问题
It's getting back.
水手 逆风 扬帆
Bosun! Head to wind! Lift the sail!
好的
Aye, aye, sir!
真他妈的 片甲不留
Bloody hell. There's nothing left.
琼斯太放肆
Jones is a loose cannon, sir.
去取亡灵箱
Fetch the chest.
总督呢？
And the governor?
他对那颗「心」颇感兴趣
He's been asking questions about the heart.
他知道其中秘密吗？
Does he know?
那他就不再有利用价值了
Then perhaps his usefulness has run its course.
快点
Step lively, men.
Step lively!
往前
Stand fast!
站稳了
Steady, men.
统统给我滚 把这可怕的东西也给我带走
Go. All of you. And take that infernal thing with you.
我不允许它上我的船
I will not have it on my ship!
实在抱歉 是我允许的
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that… because I will.
只有这样才能让这条船
Because it seems to be the only way to ensure.
遵从东印度公司的指挥
that this ship do as directed by the company.
我们需要拷问犯人
We need prisoners to interrogate,
犯人活着才能拷问
which tends to work best when they're alive.
荷兰人只听从其船长的命令
The Dutchman sails as its captain commands.
其船长也必须听从命令
And its captain is to sail it as commanded.
当我下令让你杀了你的「宠物」时 你就应该明白这个道理了
I would have thought you'd learned that when I ordered you to kill your pet.
这已经不是你的天下了 琼斯
This is no longer your world, Jones.
废物…
The immaterial has become…
终究是个废物
…immaterial.
准备 瞄准
Charge your bayonets.
我们还要这样冷战多久？
How long do we continue not talking?
救出杰克后 就没事了
Once we rescue Jack, everything'll be fine.
那就去救杰克
Then we rescue Jack.
要得到最想要的东西
For what we want most…
就要为此付出代价
…there is a cost must be paid in the end.
- 巴布萨 看前方 - 没错 我们迷失方向了
- Barbossa, ahead! - Aye, we're good and lost now.
- 迷失方向了？- 只有迷失方向
- Lost? - For certain you have to be lost.
才能到达一个无人能找到的地方
to find a place as can't be found.
不然大家都知道在哪里了
Elseways, everyone would know where it was.
- 速度在加快 - 没错
- We're gaining speed. - Aye.
各就各位
To stations!
大家各就各位
All hands to stations!
满舵 左舷 全速前进
Rudder full. Hard aport! Gather way.
不 不要动 让它朝前行
Nay! Belay that! Let her run straight and true!
啊呀
Blimey.
- 你把我们都害死了 - 不要说得这么难听
- You've doomed us all. - Don't be so unkind.
下次再走这条路可能就过不去了
You may not survive to pass this way again,
这是我最后的忠告
and these be the last friendly words you'll hear.
把它绑牢
Tie her off.
左满舵
Hard aport.
抓稳
Hold on!
投降吧 你们这群蠢货
Strike your colors, you blooming cockroaches.
死人不会告密
Dead men tell no tales.
我的花生
My peanut.
拉紧绳索 松开转帆索
Haul the halyard. Slacken braces.
是 船长 松开转帆索
Aye, captain. Slacken braces.
快点
Step lively with a will.
- 是的 是的 - 是的
- Aye, aye. - Right away, sir.
我希望下面着火了！
I want a fire down below!
- 救我！- 打起精神来 你们这帮懒虫
- Help. - Man the yards, you filthy toads.
拉呀 拉呀
Haul! Haul!
把帆准备好 准备前进
Haul the sheets handsomely. Scandalize the lateens.
- 遵命 - 遵命
- Aye, sir. - Right away, sir.
- 斯派洛先生 - 是 船长
- Mr. Sparrow? - Aye, cap'n.
你认为你绑得怎么样？
What say you about the condition of this tack line?
- 绑得蛮好啊 船长 - 绑好了？
- It be proper to my eyes, sir. - Proper?
没有绑好 也不合适 无法接受 力度不够
Lt is neither proper nor suitable, sir. It is not acceptable nor adequate.
这么明显 还敢还嘴
It is, in obvious fact, an abomination.
抱歉 船长 再给一个机会
Begging your pardon, sir, but if you gave a man another chance.
我应该吗？
Shall I?
就是你这种观念 才让我们沦落到今天这般地步
Lt's that sort of thinking got us into this mess.
船速慢了 时间浪费了
We have lost speed and, therefore, time.
宝贵的时间啊 浪费了就追不回来了
Precious time, which cannot be recovered once lost.
你们都听明白了吗？
Do you understand?
- 是 船长 - 都明白了？
- Aye, aye, captain. - Do you now?
现在都得重来
Lt will all have to be redone. All of it.
这就是散漫的下场
And let this serve as a lesson to the lot of you.
遵命 大家都在拼命地干
Doldrums, sir, has the entire crew on edge.
对于你们这帮蛆虫 我一点都不同情
I have no sympathy for any of you feculent maggots,
也不想再容忍你们了
and no more patience to pretend otherwise.
船员们 我不干这稀奇古怪的勾当了
Gentlemen, I wash my hands of this weirdness.
没风
No wind.
当然不应该有风
Of course, there's no bloody wind.
以我的灵魂发誓 来一阵微风
My soul I do swear for a breeze.
飒飒的响 轻轻的拂面而过
Gust. Whisper. A tiny, miniature lick.
是啊 我知道 但为什么啊 到底为什么啊？
Yes, sir, I know, but why? Why would he do that?
因为他傻呗 是不是啊？
Because he's a lummox, isn't he?
我们要开个隆重的庭院派对 就不请你
We shall have a magnificent garden party and you're not invited.
嘘
Shoo.
石头
A rock.
我被石头跟踪 这还是头一遭
Now we're being followed by rocks. Never had that before.
哦
Oh.
绳索
A rope.
真是不毛之地
This truly is a godforsaken place.
没看到杰克啊 一个人也看不到
I don't see Jack. I don't see anyone.
他一定在这儿
He's here.
戴维·琼斯从不会让任何人从这里逃脱
Davy Jones never once gave up that what he took.
现在说这个又有什么用？
And does it matter?
都是你害的 我们被困在这里 处境和杰克一样了
We're trapped here by your doing. No different than Jack.
杰克远在天边近在眼前
Witty Jack is closer than you think.
不可能
Impossible.
船
Boat.
好象做梦一样 真的是杰克
Slap me thrice and hand me to me mama. It's Jack.
- 是船长 - 正是我们船长
- It's the captain! - A sight for sore eyes.
把浪姆酒藏起来
Hide the rum.
- 吉布斯？- 是我 船长
- Mr. Gibbs. - Aye, cap'n.
我看也是
I thought so.
你要对你的行为负责
I expect you're able to account for your actions, then.
什么？
Sir?
这么久以来 为什么我船上纪律这么涣散
There's been a perpetual and virulent lack of discipline upon my vessel. Why?
- 为什么会这样？- 船长 你…
- Why is that, sir? - Sir, you're…
船长 你在戴维·琼斯的魔狱里
You're in Davy Jones' Locker, cap'n.
我当然知道 我知道我身处何地
I know that. I know where I am.
- 不要以为我不知道 - 杰克·斯派洛
- And don't think I don't. - Jack Sparrow.
嘿 赫克托
Oh, Hector.
好久不见
It's been too long. Hasrt it?
还记得当初 你一枪把我打死了
Aye. Isla de Muerta, remember? You shot me.
我才没有呢
No, I didn't.
提亚·朵玛 出来散步吗？
Tia Dalma, out and about, eh?
你总是给精神病人带来点死亡的快感
You add an agreeable sense of the macabre to any delirium.
他以为我们是他的幻觉
He thinks we're a hallucination.
威尔 告诉我
William, tell me something:
你是来求我救一位让人忧伤的少女
Have you come because you need my help to save a certain distressing damsel,
还是一位本就忧伤的少女？
or rather, damsel in distress? Either one.
都不是
No.
那你就不会来 也就不该在这里出现
Well, then, you wouldn't be here, would you?
你不可能来这 所以你根本不在这
So you can't be here. Q.E.D., you're not really here.
杰克
Jack.
这是真的 我们真的来了
This is real. We're here.
- 你说这里是魔狱？- 是啊
- The Locker, you say? - Aye.
我们是来救你的
We've come to rescue you.
不可能 感谢你们的好意
Have you, now? That's very kind of you.
不过我有船 你们没有
But it would seem that as I possess a ship and you don't,
你们才需要被救呢 我现在没心情救你们
you're the ones in need of rescuing, and I'm not sure as I'm in the mood.
那是我的船 就在那边
I see my ship. Right there.
看不到啊
Can't spot it.
一定是条小船 躲在黑珍珠号后面什么地方
Must be a tiny little thing hiding somewhere behind the Pearl.
杰克 贝克特勋爵已经得到了戴维·琼斯的心
Jack, Cutler Beckett has the heart of Davy Jones.
- 他控制了飞翔的荷兰人号 - 统治了整个海洋
- He controls the Flying Dutchman. - He's taking over the seas.
起义歌已经被唱了 海盗公会被召集了
The song has been sung. The Brethren Court is called.
我才走开几天 就被你们搞得天翻地覆
Leave you alone for a minute, look what happens. Everything's gone to pot.
杰克 大家需要你啊
Aye. The world needs you back something fierce.
你也需要一队船员
And you need a crew.
我为什么要和你们同船？
Why should I sail with any of you?
你们当中四个人曾想杀我 其中一个得手了
Four of you have tried to kill me in the past. One of you succeeded.
她没告诉你吗
Oh, she's not told you.
那你们就待在这里好好谈谈吧
You'll have loads to talk about while you're here.
至于你
As for you…
现在…不要跟我说你当时不爽
Now… don't tell me you didn't enjoy it at the time.
说得有理 女士 算你一个
Fair enough. All right, you're in.
不要你 你吓着我
Don't need you. You scare me.
考顿 你可以过来 马蒂吗
Gibbs, you can come. Marty. Mm…
考顿
Cotton.
鹦鹉考顿 我有点犹豫 不过起码能聊天解闷
Cottors parrot, I'm a little iffy, but at least I'll have someone to talk to.
你是谁？
Who are you?
泰洪 这些都是我的人
Tai Huang. These are my men.
- 你效忠谁？- 谁出价高 就效忠谁
- Where do your allegiances lie? - With the highest bidder.
- 我有条船 - 它使得你出价最高
- I have a ship. - That makes you the highest bidder.
好人啊 提锚扬帆 准备起航
Good man. Weigh anchor, all hands. Prepare to make sail.
起锚
Weigh anchor.
杰克
Jack…
你往哪去啊？杰克
Which way are you going, Jack?
调整船帆 松开转帆索和帆脚索
Trim that sail. Slack windward brace and sheet.
- 拉起浮标垂索 - 拉起浮标垂索
- Haul the pennant line. - Haul the pennant line.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
- 你在干嘛？- 不 我问你在干嘛？
- What are you doing? - No, what are you doing?
你是谁？船长在船上是下令的
What are you? Captain gives orders on the ship.
船长已经在下令了
The captain of the ship is giving orders.
- 我的船 我是船长 - 可航海图是我的
- My ship, makes me captain. - They be my charts.
那你也只是海图员
That makes you "chartman."
闭嘴！你们俩个！这是命令 懂吗
Stow it! The both of you! That's an order! Understand?!
对不起 既然船长位子悬而未决的话
Sorry. I just thought with the captain issue in doubt,
不妨也考虑我一下
I'd throw in my name for consideration.
对不起
Sorry.
- 我会投你的票 - 是吗？
- I'd vote for you. - Yeah?
你把杰克丢给挪威海怪了
You left Jack to the Kraken.
他已经被救了 都过去了
He's rescued now. It's done with.
我别无选择
Will, I had no choice.
你选择了对我隐瞒
You chose not to tell me.
我没办法
I couldn't.
那不该由你来承担
It wasrt your burden to bear.
但还是我承担了 不是吗？
But I did bear it, didn't I?
我只是不知道自己承担了什么？
I just didn't know what it was.
我还以为
I thought…
你以为我爱他？
You thought I loved him.
如果你凡事都独自决定 叫我怎么能信任你？
If you make your choices alone, how can I trust you?
你不能
You can't.
好可怕啊
Eerie.
毛骨悚然
That's downright macabre.
要是往他们身上丢颗炮弹会怎样？
I wonder what would happen if you dropped a cannonball on one of them?
太没礼貌了
Be disrespectful, it would.
他们本该由戴维·琼斯照顾
They should be in the care of Davy Jones.
那是他的责任
That was the duty him was charged with…
是女神科莉布索指定的
…by the goddess, Calypso.
将死于海中的灵魂送到彼岸去
To ferry those who die at sea to the other side.
每隔十年
And every ten years…
他可以上岸一次
…him could come ashore…
和真正爱他的女人欢聚
…to be with she who love him… truly.
但那个人已经变成了怪兽
But the man has become a monster.
就是说 他并非一直 是那章鱼怪的模样吗？
So he wasrt always… tentacley?
是的
No.
他曾经是个
Him was a man…
男人
…once.
有船来了
Now there's boats coming.
他们对我们没有威胁 是吧？
They're not a threat to us. Am I right?
我们对他们来说不过是鬼魂
We are nothing but ghosts to them.
让他们任意漂流吧
It's best just let them be.
那是我父亲 我们回到阳间了
It's my father. We've made it back.
父亲 我在这里
Father! Father, here, look here!
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
我们还没到阳间呢
We're not back.
父亲
Father!
伊丽莎白 你死了吗？
Elizabeth. Are you dead?
没有啊
No. No.
我应该是死了
I think I am.
不 你不能死
No, you can't be.
那就是亡灵箱
There was this chest, you see.
就一只 当时它很重要的
It's odd. At the time it seemed so important.
上船来
Come aboard.
那颗心
And a heart.
如果你插死了那颗心 你的心脏就得来顶替
I learned that if you stab the heart, yours must take its place.
你就会永远在海上航行
And you will sail the seas for eternity.
「荷兰人」号一定要有位船长
The Dutchman must have a captain.
为这个死 真不值得
Silly thing to die for.
谁扔条绳子下去 快上来啊
Someone, cast a line. Come back with us!
过来啊
Come on.
命中注定
A touch… of destiny.
抓住绳子
Take the line.
我真为你自豪 伊丽莎白
I'm so proud of you, Elizabeth.
爸爸 抓住绳子
Father, the line! Take the line!
- 她绝不能离开这船 - 爸爸
- She must not leave the ship! - Father!
求你和我们走 求你了 我不能离开你啊
Please come with us! Please! No! I won't leave you!
我会给你母亲带个好
I'll give your love to your mother.
- 求你了 我不能放手让你走 - 伊丽莎白
- Please, I won't let you go! - Elizabeth.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
有什么办法吗？
Is there a way?
他心甘情愿的
Him at peace.
没水了
No water.
为什么只剩朗姆酒了？
Why is all but the rum gone?
朗姆酒也喝没了
Rum's gone too.
如果我们入夜前还逃不出去
If we cannot escape these doldrums before night,
恐怕我们就要被困在 漫无边际的大海上
I fear we will sail on trackless seas.
永远在世界之间
Doomed to roam the reach between worlds.
永远
Forever.
没水喝才是燃眉之急
With no water, forever looks to be arriving a mite too soon.
他为什么无能为力呢？
Why doesn't he do something?
- 我的眼珠 还给我 - 实在搞不明白
- Me eye. Give it back! - There's no sense to it.
日落时才会有绿灿烂 而不是日出时
And the green flash happens at sunset, not sunrise.
「超越边缘」… 我真的要疯了
"Over the edge." Ah, it's driving me over the blooming edge.
日出时怎么会「落」呢
Sunrises don't set.
上就是下
"Up is down."
什么狗屁
Well, that's just maddeningly unelpful.
为什么总要拐弯抹角？
Why are these things never clear?
- 已经明说了 杰克 - 什么？嗯？
- Clear as mud, Jackie. - What? Eh?
- 捅那颗心 - 别捅那颗心
- Stab the heart. - Don't stab the heart.
- 怎么说？- 「荷兰人」号一定要有船长
- Come again? - The Dutchman must have a captain.
你们是在帮倒忙
That's even more than less than unelpful.
永远在海上航行
Sail the seas for eternity.
- 我喜欢海洋 - 不能上岸怎么办？
- I love the sea. - What about port?
我更喜欢朗姆酒 朗姆酒是好东西
I prefer rum. Rum's good.
上岸 就有朗姆酒和女人
Making port. Where we can get rum, and salty wenches…
- 十年一次 - 他说什么？
- Once every 10 years. - What'd he say?
- 十年一次 - 十年可是很久的
- Once every 10 years. - Ten years is a long time, mate.
要是没朗姆酒就会更久
Even longer given the deficit of rum.
但永远还是更长啊
But eternity is longer still.
那你打算如何消受永久呢？
And how will you be spending it? Dead?
死着呢？还是活着呢？
Or not?
- 不死的斯派洛船长 - 哦 我喜欢这头衔
- The immortal Captain Sparrow. - Oh, I like that.
碰到日落时也无所谓了
Come sunset, it won't matter.
不是日落
Not sunset.
日落是下
Sundown.
日出 就是上
And rise. Up.
那是什么？
What's that?
那是什么？不知道 你说呢？
What is that? I don't know. What do you think?
- 在哪里？- 在那里
- Where? - There.
是什么啊？
What is it?
他在摇晃船
He's rocking the ship.
我们在摇晃船
We're rocking the ship.
啊哈 给他破解了
Aye. He's onto it.
他在让船摇晃
He's rocking the ship.
我们把自己倒着绑在主桅上
We'll tie each other to the mast upside down,
等船翻过来 我们就朝上了
so when the boat flips we'll be the right way up.
加把力
Time it with the swell.
你们一群懒猪 快把系炮绳松开
Loose the cannons, you lazy bilge rats.
把货物解开 让它们滚起来
Unstow the cargo. Let it shift.
现在上
Now up…
就是下了
…is down.
都是你的馊主意
This was your idea.
上帝保佑
Blessed sweet westerlies!
我们回来了
We're back!
这是日出
Lt's the sunrise.
谈判
Parley?
我们得拿枪 赶快把我们解开
We need our pistols! Get untied, hurry!
好啦
All right, then!
海盗公会会在沉船湾聚会
The Brethren Court is a-gathering at Shipwreck Cove.
杰克 你和我得出席 这无可争议吧
And, Jack, you and I are a-going. There'll be no arguing that point.
当然有争议
I is arguing the point.
一群海盗成帮结伙 我可要离你们远远的
If there's pirates a-gathering, I'm pointing my ship the other way.
海盗集起来是要对付贝克特 你也是海盗的一员
The pirates are gathering to fight Beckett, and you're a pirate.
不管你愿不愿打 你跑不了 杰克
Fight or not, you're not running, Jack.
如果我们不团结 他们就会把我们一个一个干掉
If we don't stand together, they'll hunt us down one by one,
到最后只剩下你一个
till there be none left but you.
听起来不错啊 杰克·斯派洛船长 最后的海盗
Quite like the sound of that. Captain Jack Sparrow, the last pirate.
没错
Aye.
那你就得独自对付琼斯了 你对此有计划吗？
And you'll be fighting Jones alone. How does that figure into your plan?
我还在考虑
I'm still working on that.
但我绝对不回那魔狱里
But I will not be going back to the Locker, mate. Count on that.
火药湿了
Wet powder.
等等 湿归湿 还是可以当棒子用的
Wait! We can still use them as clubs!
- 哇 - 对不起 挺好用
- Ow! - Sorry. Effective, though.
这岛上有淡水
There's fresh water on this island.
我们可以先补给 然后再拼个你死我活
We can resupply there and get back to shooting each other later.
你们上岸去快活吧 我要待在我的船上
You lead the shore party. I'll stay with my ship.
我不会让你掌管我的船
I'll not be leaving my ship in your command.
你们干嘛不一起上岸 让我来掌管这船呢
Why don't you both go ashore and leave the ship in my command.
暂时性的
Temporarily.
小心船啊
Mind the boat.
- 我的天啊 - 好大的尸体啊
- Criminy. - Odds bodkins!
小心 小心
Careful! Careful!
你这条蠢鱼
You stupid fish!
实际上是头足类动物
Actually it's a cephalopod.
就算你对了吧
Serves you right.
一定有人会花钱来看的
Pin, I bet people would pay a shilling to see this.
还会有人出钱来给他们画像
And another shilling for a sketch of them sitting atop!
平特尔和瑞盖提 章鱼怪杀手
Pintel and Ragetti, Kraken slayers.
可以一块一块割了卖钱
We could serve up a slice as a souvenir.
还在想着逃跑吗？杰克
Still thinking of running, Jack?
你能跑出这个世界吗？
Think you can outrun the world?
不久 其他人逐渐死光
You know, the problem with being the last of anything…
你就是孤家寡人
…by and by, there be none left at all.
有时候事情会重复 你和我就是见证啊
Sometimes things come back, mate. We're living proof, you and me.
这就是在赌博 是吧？
Aye, but that's a gamble of long odds, ain't it?
能否回来 可不是定数
There's never a guarantee of coming back.
早晚要死倒是肯定的
But passing on, that's dead certain.
要召集海盗公会
Summoning the Brethren Court, then, is it?
我们唯一的希望了
Lt's our only hope, lad.
这话太让人心寒了
That's a sad commentary in and of itself.
这世界曾经很大
The world used to be a bigger place.
世界还是一样大
The world's still the same.
只是我们的空间小了
There's just… less in it.
水中有毒 被尸体污染了
Poisoned. Fouled by the body.
我在新加坡见过这人
Eh, I know him. He was in Singapore!
- 新加坡 - 船长
- Singapore. - Captain!
嗬！
Hoy!
有人来了
We got company!
他才是船长
He's the captain.
邵峰
Sao Feng…
你出现在这真是太巧了
…you showing up here, it is truly a remarkable coincidence.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
你曾经羞辱过我
You paid me great insult once.
这听起来不像是我的为人啊
That doesn't sound like me.
我们这就算扯平了如何？
Shall we just call it square, then?
放了她
Release her.
- 她不在交易之中 - 什么交易？
- She's not part of the bargain. - And what bargain be that?
你们听见特纳船长的话了？
You heard Captain Turner.
- 放开她 - 特纳船长？
- Release her! - "Captain Turner"?
这臭小子背信弃义
Aye, the perfidious rotter led a mutiny against us!
我需要黑珍珠号来救回我父亲
I need the Pearl to free my father.
这是我参与的唯一原因
That's the only reason I came on this voyage.
为什么你不告诉你的计划？
Why didn't you tell me you were planning this?
这是我肩负的使命
Lt was my burden to bear.
他需要黑珍珠号 特纳船长需要黑珍珠号
He needs the Pearl. Captain Turner needs the Pearl.
你现在感到内疚了 你和你的海盗公会
And you felt guilty. And you and your Brethren Court.
就没人只是因为想我才来救我的吗？
Did no one come to save me just because they missed me?
我站在他们一边
I'm standing with them.
对不起 杰克 有位老朋友想要先见见你
I'm sorry, Jack, but there is an old friend who wants to see you first.
这老朋友会不会要我的命呢？
I'm not certain I can survive any more visits from old friends.
这是你的机会去找出答案
Here is your chance to find out.
很奇怪啊
Curious.
你的朋友看起来很绝望啊 杰克
Your friends appear to be quite desperate, Jack.
他们不再相信一群乌合之众
Perhaps they no longer believe that a gathering of squabbling pirates.
能打赢飞翔的荷兰人号
can defeat the Flying Dutchman.
绝望可以导致背叛
And so despair leads to betrayal.
背叛对你我来说并不陌生 是吧？
But you and I are no strangers to betrayal, are we?
不在这 杰克
Lt's not here, Jack.
什么？什么不在
What? What isn't?
戴维·琼斯的心脏 安全的存放在荷兰人号上
The heart of Davy Jones. It's safely aboard the Dutchman,
你没法用它来
and so unavailable for use as leverage.
偿还你欠船长的债了
to satisfy your debt to the good captain.
在我看来 我的债已经偿还了
By my reckoning, that account has been settled.
除非你死
By your death?
但你还活着
And yet here you are.
闭上眼 假装这是一场恶梦
Close your eyes and pretend it's all a bad dream.
我就是这么活过来的
That's how I get by.
但如果戴维·琼斯知道你活着呢？
And if Davy Jones were to learn of your survival?
船桨
Ship oars.
注意了 船员们
Be on your guard, men.
我的人足够驾驭珍珠号
My men are crew enough.
公司的船当然要用我们自己的人
Company ship, company crew.
你答应过黑珍珠号归我的
You agreed. The Black Pearl was to be mine.
你不是当过了吗
And so it was.
也许你会考虑其他方案
Perhaps you'll consider an alternative arrangement.
你什么都不需要付出 只要出一点信息而已
One which requires absolutely nothing from you but information.
肯定是海盗公会的事了 作为交换
Regarding the Brethren Court, no doubt. In exchange for fair compensation?
结清我欠琼斯的债
Square my debt with Jones…
保证我的自由 可以吗？
…guarantee my freedom?
当然了
Of course.
这是桩不错的生意
It's just good business.
趁我我心情好 你想让我告诉你什么呢？
Were I in a divulgatory mood, what then might I divulge?
一切
Everything.
会议在哪举行？
Where are they meeting?
海盗王都是谁？
Who are the pirate lords?
九枚西班牙银币的用处是什么？
What is the purpose of the nine pieces of eight?
准备一下船
Prepare the brig.
贝克特同意把黑珍珠号给我的
Beckett agreed the Black Pearl was to be mine.
贝克特爵士不会放弃一艘 能赢过荷兰人号的船 对吗？
He's not going to give up the only ship as can outrun the Dutchman, is he?
他们是不会遵守诺言的 是吗？
Shame they're not bound to honor the code of the Brethren, isn't it?
这年头已经没有信誉可言了
Because honor's a hard thing to come by nowadays.
我也没必要和输家为伍
There is no honor to remaining with the losing side.
见风转舵是最明智的选择
Leaving it for the winning side, that's just good business.
- 你是说输家吗？- 他们有荷兰人号
- The losing side, you say? - They have the Dutchman.
现在珍珠号也归他们了
Now the Pearl!
海盗公会还有什么？
And what do the Brethren have?
我们有科莉布索（海中女神）
We have Calypso.
科莉布索
Calypso.
古老传说而已
An old legend.
不 女神被封印在凡人体内
No. The goddess herself, bound in human form.
想一想 利用海洋的力量 用来对付我们的敌人
Imagine all the power of the seas brought to bear against our enemy.
我要把她释放出来 但为此我需要召集公会
I intend to release her. But for that I need the Brethren Court.
所有的海盗王
All the Court.
那你就监禁巴罗萨
You can keep Barbossa.
那个残暴的小人 还他那个木头眼睛的小跟屁虫
The belligerent homunculus and his friend with the wooden eye, both.
还有特纳 尤其是特纳
And Turner. Especially Turner.
其他人跟我上珍珠号 然后带你去沉船湾
The rest go with me on the Pearl. I'll lead you to Shipwreck Cove,
我把海盗们交给你 但你不能把我交给琼斯
where I will hand you the pirates and you will not hand me to Jones.
- 很公平吧 你觉得呢？- 那斯旺小姐怎么办？
- Bloody fair deal, don't you think? - And what becomes of Miss Swann?
你对她有何兴趣？
What interest is she to you?
你有什么建议？船长
What are you proposing, captain?
你打算接受什么呢？船长
What be accepting, cap'n?
- 那女孩 - 什么？
- The girl. - What?
杰克
Jack.
我刚刚想起
I've just recalled.
我有个神奇的罗盘 能指向我想去的地方
I've got this wonderful compass, which points to whatever I want.
那我还要你做什么呢？
So for what do I need you?
伊丽莎白不能用来做交易
Elizabeth is not part of any bargain.
同意
Out of the question.
这不是个问题
It was not a question.
指向你最想要的东西
Points to the thing you want most.
而那不是海盗公会吧？
And that is not the Brethren Court, is it?
- 那是什么呢？杰克 - 是我
- Then what is, Jack? - Me.
- 让我死 - 成交
- Dead. - Done.
什么 不行
What? Not done.
是你让我们陷入困境的 如果能让我们找到出路 就成交
You got us into this. If it frees us, then done!
该死
Damn.
但是 如果我杀了你
Although, if I kill you, then I can use the compass.
就可以自己用罗盘来找到沉船湾了
to find Shipwreck Cove, is it, on my own.
而不需要中间人了
Cut out the middle man, as it were.
伊丽莎白 他们是海盗
Elizabeth, they are pirates.
我和海盗打交道也不止一次两次了
I have had more than enough experience dealing with pirates!
那我们达成共识了？
Then we have an accord?
把我杀了 你自己找到海湾
With me killed, you'd arrive at the cove,
发现那是一个攻不破的堡垒
find it a stronghold, nigh impregnable…
足以顶住数年的封锁
…able to withstand blockade for years.
那时就会想 要是当初没杀某人
Then you'd be wishing, "lf only there was someone I had not killed inside.
就能让海盗们自投罗网了
to ensure that the pirates then come outside."
你能做到这些吗？
And you can accomplish all this?
士可杀不可辱
You may kill me, but you may never insult me.
我是谁？
Who am I?
我是杰克·斯派洛船长啊
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
成交
Done!
有人落水！
Man overboard!
你疯了
You're mad.
谢天谢地 不然我还没这个胆儿呢
Thank goodness. If I wasrt, this'd probably never work.
我连一滴朗姆酒都没喝哦
And that was without even a single drop of rum.
把这个胆小的令人厌恶的叛徒关进船舱
Send this pestilent, traitorous, cowhearted, yeasty codpiece to the brig.
我们该追哪条船？
Which ship do we follow?
发信号让荷兰人号盯住邵峰 我们跟着珍珠号
Signal the Dutchman to track down Sao Feng. We follow the Pearl.
我们要多少时间才可以出发？
How soon can we have the ship ready to pursue?
她下来了
She's going down!
站直了
Stand clear!
他是事先都计划好了 还是随时起意呢？
Do you think he plans it all out, or just makes it up as he goes along?
船长
Sir.
明天此时 我们就能抵达沉船湾 到时你就自由了
By this time tomorrow, we will arrive at Shipwreck Cove and you will be free.
科莉布索
Calypso.
什么？
Excuse me?
你的称呼很多 你可能不会喜欢这个
Not a name you fancy, I imagine, out of the many that you have…
但是我们就这么称呼你了
…but it is what we call you.
我们是指谁？
We being who?
你承认了
You confirm it.
承认什么了？
Confirm what?
- 你什么都没告诉我 - 是海盗公会 不是我
- You've told me nothing. - The Brethren Court, not I.
第一届公会做出的这一决定 我本该反对的
The First Brethren Court, whose decision I would have opposed.
他们把你封印在凡人体内
They bound you to human form.
使得海洋的掌握权落在人类的手中 而不是…
so the rule of the seas would belong to man and not…
掌握在我手上
To me.
你的原身不应被封印
But one such as you should never be anything less than what you are.
谢谢统治者的美言
Pretty speech from a captor.
但你在牢狱外甜言蜜语是不能打动我的
But words whispered through prison bars lose their charm.
会因为我的努力而责怪我吗？
Can I be blamed for my efforts?
虽然危险 世上男人都向往大海
All men are drawn to the sea, perilous though it may be.
有人把欲望当作开脱罪行的借口
And some men offer desire as justification for their crimes.
我只是说出我的欲望而已
I offer simply my desire.
而作为报答呢？
And in return?
我想要你的恩赐 假如你肯赐予的话
I would have your gifts, should you choose to give them.
如果我不想赐予呢？
And if I should choose not?
那我就接受…
Then I will take…
…你的愤怒
…your fury.
邵峰？
Sao Feng?
请过来
Here.
Please.
收齐九枚银币
With all nine pieces of eight…
你就会自由
…you will be free.
拿着
Take it!
你现在是船长了
You are captain now.
我？
Me?
接替我的职位 去沉船湾
Go in my place to Shipwreck Cove.
船长 船被抢了 我们顶不住了
Captain! The ship is taken. We cannot…
原谅我 科莉布索
Forgive me… Calypso.
邵
Sao.
他对你说什么了？
What did he tell you?
他让我作船长
He made me captain.
准备 开火
Set! Fire!
你不是我的船长
You are not my captain.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
詹姆斯 詹姆斯
James. James.
谢天谢地你还活着
Thank God, you're alive.
你父亲见到你平安
Your father'll be overjoyed.
- 会很高兴的 - 我父亲已经死了
- to know you're safe. - My father's dead.
不可能 他回英国了
No, that can't be true. He returned to England.
是贝克特爵士告诉你的吗？
Did Lord Beckett tell you that?
你们现在的船长是谁？
Who among you do you name as captain?
船长 她
Captain. Her.
是她
Her.
船长？
Captain?
把船拖走 把囚犯们关起来
Tow the ship. Put the prisoners in the brig.
船长住我的房间
The captain shall have my quarters.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you, sir.
- 但我宁愿和我的船员待在一起 - 伊丽莎白
- But I prefer to remain with my crew. - Elizabeth.
我发誓
I swear.
我不知道
I did not know.
不知道什么？你站哪一边？
Know what? Which side you chose?
你现在知道了吧
Well, now you do.
系带王
Bootstrap?
Bootstrap.
比尔·特纳？
Bill Turner?
系带王
Bootstrap.
你知道我的名字？
You know my name.
是的 我认识你的儿子
Yes, I know your son.
威尔·特纳
Will Turner.
威廉？
William.
他成功了 他还活着
He made it. He's alive.
是他派你告诉我 他要来救我了
And now he sends you to tell me that he's coming to get me.
哈哈 谢天谢地 他要来了
God's wounds. He's on his way.
是的 威尔还活着
Yes, Will is alive.
他很想帮助你
And he wants to help you.
他帮不了我 他不会来的
He can't help me. He won't come.
你是他的父亲
But you're his father.
我认识你
I know you.
他提起过你
He spoke of you.
他救不了我 他是因为你才来不了
He can't save me. He can't come because of you.
因为我？
Me?
你是伊丽莎白吧
You're Elizabeth.
是的 我是伊丽莎白
Yes, I'm Elizabeth.
如果琼斯被杀 杀他的人就必须替代他的职位
If Jones be slain, he who slays him must take his place.
作船长 永远
Captain… Forever.
荷兰人号总要有一个船长的
The Dutchman must always have a captain.
如果他救了我
And if he saves me…
他便会失去你
…he loses you.
我知道
I see.
他不会选我的
He won't pick me.
我也不会选自己的
I wouldn't pick me.
告诉他别来
Tell him not to come.
告诉他离的远远的
Tell him to stay away.
告诉他太迟了
Tell him it's too late.
我已经是船的一部分了
I'm already a part of the ship…
船员的一份子了
…and the crew.
系带王
Bootstrap.
你知道我的名字？
You know my name.
是的 我认识你的儿子
Yes, I know your son.
威廉
William.
他来救我了
He's coming for me.
等着瞧吧
Wait and see.
你会看到的
You'll see.
他答应过的
He promised.
把她吊过来
Swing her over.
准备绳索
Ready those lines.
长官
Sir.
刻意留下的标记
A breadcrumb trail.
- 以便我们顺藤摸瓜 - 他们之中有个叛徒？
- And we're meant to follow. - A betrayer among them?
- 还是陷阱？- 对手的一步高棋
- Or a trap? - A gambit by a skilled opponent.
- 改路线 上尉 - 长官？
- Adjust course, lieutenant. - Sir?
希望在到达终点时
We can only hope to reach our destination.
船上的人不会被杀光
before they run out of bodies.
你逃出来比我想的还要快
You escaped the brig even quicker than I expected.
威廉 你发现什么了吗？
William, do you notice anything?
当然
Rather…
你发现什么不该被发现的吧？
…do you notice something that is not there to be noticed?
- 你并没有通知大家？- 奇怪吧？
- You haven't raised an alarm. - Odd, isn't it?
没有你这招儿怪
Not as odd as this.
你自己的主意？
Come up with this all by your lonesome, did you?
我问自己：「杰克这时会怎么做」
I said to myself, "Think like Jack."
然后就想出这招儿了？
This is what you've arrived at?
带贝克特爵士到沉船湾 争取他的信任
Lead Beckett to Shipwreck Cove so as to gain his trust…
然后救出你父亲
…accomplish your own ends?
看起来你完全不了解我嘛
Lt's like you don't know me at all.
你的亲密爱人对此计划有何感想啊
And how does your dearly beloved feel about this plan?
哈哈
Ah.
你还没告诉她
You've not seen fit to trust her with it.
我要失去她了 杰克
I'm losing her, Jack.
我离我父亲越近 就离伊丽莎白越远
Every step I make for my father is a step away from Elizabeth.
如果你满腔投入 一定会全盘皆输
If you choose to lock your heart away, you'll lose her for certain.
让我来给你指点指点
If I might lend a machete to your intellectual thicket…
置身事外
…avoid the choice altogether.
换个角度
Change the facts.
找个人来干掉琼斯
Let someone else dispatch Jones.
谁？
Who?
你？
You?
要是我们换一下就都解决了
Death has a curious way of reshuffling one's priorities.
我溜上荷兰人号 找到心脏 捅那个乱跳的东西一刀
I slip aboard the Dutchman, find the heart, stab the beating thing,
你父亲的债就清了
your father's free from his debt,
你也能和你迷人的小情人一起了
you're free to be with your charming murderess.
你愿意切下自己的心脏 把自己和荷兰人号永远绑在一起吗？
You're willing to cut out your heart and bind yourself to the Dutchman…
- 永远？- 不 伙计 那我就永远自由了
- Forever? - No, mate. I'm free forever.
可以自由穿越地图外的海域 没有死亡的束缚了
Free to sail the seas beyond the edges of the map. Free from death itself.
你必须得尽责 杰克
You have to do the job though, Jack.
你得载灵魂去阴间
You have to ferry souls to the next world.
不然就得像琼斯那样
Or end up just like Jones.
我脸上不适合长触须
I don't have the face for tentacles.
作为活人就会有牵挂啊
But immortal has to count for something, eh?
要这来干嘛？
What's this for?
从我的角度出发 你会想到的
Think like me. It'll come to you.
替我向戴维·琼斯问好
My regards to Davy Jones.
我恨他
I hate him.
跟我来
Come with me.
快点
Quickly.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
选择
Choosing a side.
不要去沉船湾 贝克特知道海盗公会在那开会
Do not go to Shipwreck Cove. Beckett knows of the meeting of the Brethren.
我觉得那里面有奸细
I fear there may be a traitor among them.
现在才求我原谅太晚了.
It's too late to earn my forgiveness.
我与你父亲的死毫无关系
I had nothing to do with your father's death.
我知道这不能赎去我以往的罪行
But that does not absolve me of my other sins.
跟我们一起走
Come with us.
詹姆斯 跟我走
James, come with me.
谁在那
Who goes there?
走 我跟着你
Go. I will follow.
你在骗人
You're lying.
我们命运交缠 伊丽莎白
Our destinies have been entwined, Elizabeth…
但无缘结连理
…but never joined.
快
Go, now.
回你的岗位去 水手
Back to your station, sailor.
- 没人能从船上逃走 - 退下 这是命令
- No one leaves the ship. - Stand down. That's an order.
这是命令
That's an order.
船员的一份子 船的一部分
Part of the crew, part of the ship.
船员的一份子 船的一部分 船员的一份子…
Part of the crew, part of the ship. Part of the crew…
- 冷静点 伙计 - 船员的一份子 船的一部分
- Steady, man. - Part of the crew, part of the ship.
注意 有人逃跑
All hands, prisoner escape!
- 退下 - 詹姆斯
- Belay that! - James!
有人逃跑
Prisoner escape!
詹姆斯 不
James! No!
- 船长死了 - 船长死了
- The admiral's dead. - Admiral's dead?
- The admiral's dead. - Admiral's dead.
- 去船长舱 - 嗯
- To the captairs cabin! - Aye!
回船上去
Back to the ship.
詹姆斯·诺灵顿 你害怕死亡吗？
James Norrington. Do you fear death?
不怕
I take that as a "no."
好剑
Nice sword.
荷兰人号受我指挥
The Dutchman is under my command.
现在是了
For now.
打起精神 注意观察
Look alive and keep a weather eye.
沉船岛不是白叫的
Not for naught it's called Shipwreck Island.
那里有沉船湾和沉船镇
Where lies Shipwreck Cove and the town of Shipwreck.
听到没有 快去
You heard him. Step lively.
都说海盗很聪明
For all that pirates are clever clogs,
其实我们在命名上很没想象力
we are unimaginative when it comes to naming things.
是
Aye.
我曾碰到过个家伙 丢了两只胳膊一只眼睛
I once sailed with a geezer who lost both of his arms and part of his eye.
你管他叫什么？
What'd you call him?
拉里
Larry.
谈好的交易我是不会赖帐的
I do not renege on a bargain once struck.
不过我们只定了结局
But we agreed on ends only.
手段由我来决定
The means are mine to decide.
当心 巴布萨
Caution, Barbossa.
别忘了是我的力量让你起死回生
Do not forget it was by my power you return from the dead.
否则结果会如何
Or what it mean if you fail me.
你别忘了你为何救我回来
Don't you forget why you had to bring me back.
为何不能让杰克 走他该走的路
Why I could not leave Jack to his well-deserved fate.
九个海盗王合力 才能封印你 科莉布索
It took nine pirate lords to bind you, Calypso.
要解封你至少也要九个
And it'll take no less than nine to set you free.
平特尔和瑞盖提船副
Masters Pintel and Ragetti.
把这个卖鱼婆关起来
Take this fishwife to the brig.
这边请 鱼婆小姐
Right this way, Mrs. Fish.
我可不是什么杂种狗 任你呼来唤去
I cannot be summoned like some mongrel pup.
你不是来了吗
Apparently, you can.
我相信你们认识
I believe you know each other.
回来当我的船员 特纳船副？
Come to join my crew again, Master Turner?
不是你的
Not yours.
他的
His.
杰克·斯派洛向你问好
Jack Sparrow sends his regards.
斯派洛？
Sparrow?
你没告诉他
You didn't tell him.
我们从魔狱里 救出了杰克和黑珍珠号
We rescued Jack from the Locker along with the Black Pearl.
你还有什么没告诉我的？
What else have you not told me?
还有个极为棘手的问题
There is an issue far more troublesome.
我相信你熟悉一个叫科莉布索的人
I believe you're familiar with a person called Calypso.
她不是人
Not a person.
是异教的神明
A heathen god.
她以最狂野的梦想来 诅咒男人们 并以此为乐
One who delights in cursing men with their wildest dreams.
然后戳穿梦想 只剩 空洞虚无和灰烬
and then revealing them to be hollow and naught but ash.
- 这世界已经摆脱她了 - 其实没全摆脱
- The world is well rid of her. - Not quite so well, actually.
海盗公会正打算释放她
The Brethren Court intends to release her.
不！他们不能！
No! They cannot!
第一届公会答应永远囚禁她的
The First Court promised to imprison her forever.
- 那是我们的约定 - 你们的约定？
- That was our agreement. - Your agreement?
我告诉他们如何封印她
I showed them how to bind her.
她不可信任
She could not be trusted.
她…让我别无选择
I… She gave me no choice.
我们必须赶在他们释放她之前动手
We must act before they release her.
你爱过她
You loved her.
她就是你情人
She's the one.
然后你背叛了她
And then you betrayed her.
她假装爱过我
She pretended to love me.
她背叛了我
She betrayed me.
我想知道 哪次背叛之后 你切出了自己的心？
And after which betrayal did you cut out your heart, I wonder.
不要惹我
Do not test me.
我还没喝完
I hadrt finished that.
你会释放我父亲的
You will free my father.
你要保证伊丽莎白的安全
And you will guarantee Elizabeth's safety.
还有我的安全
Along with my own.
你要求不低 特纳先生
Your terms are steep, Mr. Turner.
我们要等价的回报
We will expect fair value in return.
我只接受一个价钱
There is only one price I will accept:
杀了科莉布索
Calypso murdered.
科莉布索在黑珍珠号上
Calypso's aboard the Black Pearl.
杰克驾黑珍珠号去了沉船湾
Jack has sailed the Black Pearl to Shipwreck Cove.
你现在不在那船上 又打算如何领我们去？
And with you no longer aboard her, how do you propose to lead us there?
你最想要什么？
What is it you want most?
看看它们！
Look at them all.
我们这辈子还没有这样的集会
There's not been a gathering like this in our lifetime.
而我欠了他们一身债
And I owe them all money.
作为会议召集人
As he who issued summons,
我宣布第四届海盗公会开幕
I convene this, the Fourth Brethren Court.
为了证实你们的身份和权力
To confirm your lordship and right to be heard,
请出示西班牙银币 诸位船长们
present now your pieces of eight, my fellow cap'ns.
这哪是西班牙银币 这是一堆破烂
Those aren't pieces of eight. They're just pieces of junk.
是 本来是要用九块 西班牙银币来封印科莉布索的
Aye. The original plan was to use nine pieces of eight to bind Calypso.
但第一届公会开会时 人人都穷得要死
But when the First Court met, the Brethren were to a one skint broke.
那改改名字吧
So change the name.
怎么 要叫「当时我们 口袋里随便什么零碎」？
To "nine pieces of whatever we happened to have in our pockets at the time?"
是 那倒是很海盗化
Oh, yes. That sounds very piratey.
瑞盖提船副 请了
Master Ragetti, if you will.
我会替你保管好的 就像你给我时说的那样
I kept it safe, just like you said when you gave it to me.
我是说过 现在我要拿回来
Aye, you have. But now I need it back.
斯派洛？
Sparrow.
我要指出我们还少一个海盗王
Might I point out that we are still short one pirate lord,
我可以等着邵峰来 一点都不急
and I'm as content as a cucumber to wait until Sao Feng joins us.
邵峰死了
Sao Feng is dead.
他死于飞翔的荷兰人号之手
He fell to the Flying Dutchman.
那条灾难之船！
The plagued ship.
他让你当船长了？船长的头衔他们就这样拱手送人？
He made you captain? They're giving the bloody title away now.
- 送他们下地狱！- 听我说
- Que lo manden al diablo! - Listen. Listen to me.
我们的位置被出卖了
Our location has been betrayed.
琼斯受贝克特勋爵指挥 正朝这里来
Jones is under the command of Lord Beckett. They're on their way here.
- 谁是叛徒？- 不太可能是我们当中的人
- Who is this betrayer? - Not likely anyone among us.
- 威尔在哪里？- 不在我们当中
- Where's Will? - Not among us.
问题不是他们怎么找到的 问题是
It matters not how they found us. The question is,
我们现在怎么办
what will we do now that they have?
我们战斗
We fight.
沉船湾是个堡垒
Shipwreck Cove is a fortress.
是个给养充足的堡垒
A well-supplied fortress.
他们攻不进来 我们就不必战斗
There is no need to fight if they cannot get to us.
可能还有第三条出路
There be a third course.
另一个时代 就在这里
In another age, at this very spot,
第一届海盗公会抓住了女海神 将她封印起来
the First Brethren Court captured the sea goddess and bound her in her bones.
那是个错误
That was a mistake.
的确 我们驯服海洋为己所用
Oh, we tamed the seas for ourselves, aye.
却为贝克特和他的同党打开了大门
But opened the door to Beckett and his ilk.
以前更美好的日子里 控制海洋不是
Better were the days when mastery of seas.
靠与可怖的怪物做交易
came not from bargains struck with eldritch creatures,
而是靠额头的汗水 凭自己的力量
but from the sweat of a mars brow and the strength of his back alone.
你们都知道这是真的
You all know this to be true.
先生们！
Gentlemen.
女士们！
Ladies.
我们要解封科莉布索
We must free Calypso.
- 开枪打他 - 切舌头！
- Shoot him. - Cut out his tongue!
打他 然后切舌头 再打舌头 剪了他乱七八糟的胡子
Shoot him, cut out his tongue, then shoot his tongue. And trim that beard.
- 邵峰会赞同巴布萨的 - 是
- Sao Feng would've agreed with Barbossa. - Ay.
科莉布索那时是我们的敌人 现在还会是
Calypso was our enemy then, she will be our enemy now.
她的脾气暴躁 现在也不可能变好
It's unlikely her mood's improved.
我赞同邵峰 放了科莉布索
I would still agree with Sao Feng. We release Calypso.
- 你威胁我？- 你给我闭嘴
- You threaten me? - I silence you.
- 真是疯狂 - 这是政治
- This is madness. - This is politics.
与此同时敌人正向 我们压过来
Meanwhile, our enemies are bearing down upon us.
说不定已经到了
If they not be here already.
我的甜心
My sweet.
你来救我了
You come for me.
- 你在等着我来 - 被困在这个躯体里
- You were expecting me. - It has been torture.
是一种折磨
Trapped in this single form.
被切断了与海的联系
Cut off from the sea.
和我所爱的一切
From all that I love.
还有你
From you.
我为你交付的任务工作了十年
Ten years I devoted to the duty you charged to me.
我照顾了那些海上死者十年
Ten years I looked after those who died at sea.
我们终于可以在一起时…
And, finally, when we could be together again…
…你没去
…you werert there.
你为什么没去？
Why werert you there?
是我的天性
Lt's my nature.
如果我不是我 你还会爱我吗
Would you love me if I was anything but what I am?
我不爱你
I do not love you.
你有很多个性 戴维·琼斯
Many things you were, Davy Jones.
但从不残酷
But never cruel.
你已经背叛了你的初衷
You have corrupted your purpose…
背叛了你自己
…and so your self.
曾经属于我的东西 已经被你藏起来了
And you did hide away what should always have been mine.
科莉布索
Calypso.
我会自由的
I will be free.
那时我会给你我的心
And when I am, I would give you my heart.
我们会永远在一起
And we would be together always.
如果那时你有心相爱
If only you had a heart to give.
你为什么来？
Why did you come?
你给囚禁你的人们 准备了什么样的命运？
And what fate have you planned for your captors?
海盗公会？
The Brethren Court?
他们临死前会明白
All of them, the last thing they will learn in this life…
我可以变得多残酷
…is how cruel I can be.
而你的命运呢？戴维·琼斯？
And what of your fate, Davy Jones?
我的心永远属于你
My heart will always belong to you.
第一届公会囚禁了科莉布索
Lt was the First Court what imprisoned Calypso.
我们这届应该放了她
We should be the ones to set her free.
为了感谢我们 她会给我们好处
And in her gratitude, she will see fit to grant us boons.
谁的好处？你的好处？
Whose boons? Your boons?
我说全是骗人的废话
Utterly deceptive twaddle-speak, says I.
如果你有更好的主意 请共享出来
If you have a better alternative, please, share.
乌贼
Cuttlefish.
对
Aye.
亲爱的朋友们 让我们
Let us not, dear friends,
不要忘记亲爱的乌贼朋友
forget our dear friends, the cuttlefish.
滑腻腻的小香肠们
Flipping glorious little sausages.
把两个乌贼放一块 它们会 毫不犹豫地自相残杀
Pen them up together, they'll devour each other without a second thought.
人的本性 不是吗？
Human nature, isn't it?
或是…鱼的本性
Or… Or fish nature.
我们可以躲在这里 给养充足武备齐全
So, yes, we could hole up here well-provisioned and well-armed.
但一个月内会死一半人
Half of us would be dead within the month.
不管怎么看结局都很悲观 或者…
Which seems quite grim to me, any way you slice it. Or…
或者像我们有才的同事 天真地建议
As my learned colleague so naively suggests,
我们放了科莉布索 然后寄希望于她的怜悯
we can release Calypso, and we can pray that she will be merciful.
但我很怀疑
I rather doubt it.
我们可以假装她绝不是个
Can we pretend she's anything other than a woman scorned.
怒火满腔的女人吗？我们不能
like which fury hell hath no? We cannot.
事物自道缘由 一旦将她放归大海
Res ipsa loquitur, tabula in naufragio.
我们只剩一个选择
We are left with but one option.
我同意…我不敢相信我正说这话
I agree with, and I cannot believe the words are coming out of me mouth…
斯旺船长 我们必须战斗
…Captain Swann. We must fight.
- 你总是逃避战斗 - 我没有
- You've always run away from a fight. - Have not.
- 你有 - 我没有
- Have so. - Have not.
- 你有 - 我没有！
- Have so. - Have not!
- 你有 你自己知道 - 没有 造谣中伤
- You have so, and you know it. - Have not. Slander and calumny.
我只是遵循最古老 最神圣的海盗传统
I have only ever embraced that oldest and noblest of pirate traditions.
此时此刻我建议 我们都应该做的事
I submit that here now that is what we all must do:
我们必须战斗
We must fight…
以便逃跑
…to run away.
- 对 - 对！
- Aye! - Aye!
海盗法典规定 战争 就是现在的情形
As per the code, an act of war, and this be exactly that,
只能由海盗大帝来宣布
can only be declared by the pirate king.
- 你编的 - 我编的？
- You made that up. - Did I, now?
我有请法典的保管人蒂格船长
I call on Cap'n Teague, keeper of the code.
松巴吉爵士宣布这全是假的！
Sri Sumbhajee proclaims this all to be folly!
去他妈的海盗法典 谁在乎…
Hang the code. Who cares a…
法典至高无上
Code is the law.
你挡我道了 孩子
You're in my way, boy.
- 法典 - 法典
- The code. - The code.
由摩根和巴多罗米尔制定的
As set forth by Morgan and Bartholomew.
- 这不可能…这怎么… - 海龟 伙计
- That can't… How did… - Sea turtles, mate.
海龟
Sea turtles.
啊 巴布萨是对的
Ah. Barbossa is right.
等一下
Hang on a minute.
海盗大帝的责任是宣战
"Lt shall be the duties, as the king,
以及与共同的敌人进行谈判
to declare war, parley with shared adversaries…"
想象一下
Fancy that.
自第一届以来就没有海盗大帝了
There has not been a king since the First Court.
现在也不太可能会变
And that's not likely to change.
- 不太可能 - 为什么？
- Not likely. - Why not?
海盗大帝是由海盗王们公选出来的
See, the pirate king is elected by popular vote.
所有海盗都只会选他自己
And each pirate only ever votes for hisself.
我提议投票
I call for a vote.
我投安曼海盗
I vote for Ammand the corsair.
法国穷光蛋夏威尔船长
Capitaine Chevalle, the penniless Frenchman.
松巴吉爵士投松巴吉爵士
Sri Sumbhajee votes for Sri Sumbhajee.
清夫人
Mistress Ching.
久卡德先生
Gentleman Jocard.
- 伊丽莎白·斯旺 - 巴布萨
- Elizabeth Swann. - Barbossa.
维基勒巴！
Vallenueva!
伊丽莎白·斯旺
Elizabeth Swann.
- 什么？- 我知道 很好奇吧？
- What? - I know. Curious, isn't it?
投票选我 投票选我
Vote for me. Vote for me.
你在说什么呀？
What you talking about?
不！
No!
那么你们的投票不打算遵循海盗法典？
Am I to understand that you lot will not be keeping to the code, then?
很好
Very well.
斯旺船长 海盗大帝 你要下什么命令？
What say you, Captain Swann, king of the Brethren Court?
预备所有的船
Prepare every vessel that floats.
黎明时
At dawn…
我们开战
…we're at war.
那么 我们将开战
And so we shall go to war.
怎么了？
What?
你什么都见过 什么都做过了 你活下来了
You've seen it all, done it all. You survived.
一定有要诀吧？为了生存？
That's the trick, isn't it? To survive?
目的不在于永远活着 杰克
Lt's not just about living forever, Jackie.
要诀是永远活出自己
The trick is living with yourself forever.
妈妈呢？
How's Mum?
她看来气色很好
She looks great.
敌人来了！消灭他们！
The enemy is here! Let's take them!
弃船！弃船！
Abandon ship. Abandon ship.
谈判？
Parley?
原来是你这杂种引狼入室
You be the cur that led these wolves to our door.
不要怪特纳 他不过是被利用的工具而已
Don't blame Turner. He was merely the tool of your betrayal.
如果你要找主谋 往你左边看
If you wish to see its grand architect, look to your left.
我没插手过这事
My hands are clean in this.
看起来是
Figuratively.
这是我自己的选择 我有自己的目的
My actions were my own and to my own purpose.
- 跟杰克没关系 - 说得好 听听工具怎么说的
- Jack had nothing to do with it. - Well spoke. Listen to the tool.
威尔 我上过荷兰人号
Will, I've been aboard the Dutchman.
我明白你的目的和重担 但恐怕那已经毫无意义了
I understand the burden you bear, but I fear that cause is lost.
只要有一个傻瓜留下来战斗 就不会没有意义
No cause is lost if there is but one fool left to fight for it.
如果特纳不是为你效劳 他怎么会给我这个？
If Turner wasrt acting on your behalf, then how did he come to give me this?
杰克你我有交易 把所有海盗送到我手上 现在他们都到了
You made a deal with me, Jack, to deliver the pirates. And here they are.
别害臊 尽管上来领赏
Don't be bashful. Step up. Claim your reward.
你欠我的帐还是要还的
Your debt to me is still to be satisfied.
在荷兰人号上服务一百年 这是起码的
One hundred years in servitude aboard the Dutchman. As a start.
欠账已经还了 在她的帮助下
That debt was paid, mate. With some help.
- 你逃跑了 - 严格来讲…
- You escaped. - Technically.
我建议交换人质
I propose an exchange.
威尔跟我们走
Will leaves with us…
你可以带走杰克
…and you can take Jack.
成交
Done.
- 取消 - 成交
- Undone. - Done.
杰克是九大海盗王之一 你没有权力
Jack's one of the nine pirate lords. You have no right.
我是海盗大帝
King.
- 听从您的命令 陛下 - 蠢才！
- As you command, your nibs. - Blackguard!
你如果有什么想说的 我也有要说的
Lf ye have something to say, I might be saying something as well.
看谁先到终点？
First to the finish, then?
你怕死吗？
Do you fear death?
你不明白的
You've no idea.
敬告你的海盗们
Advise your Brethren,
你们可以战斗 但都会被消灭
you can fight, and all of you will die.
如果不战斗 你们大部分人会死
Or you can not fight, in which case only most of you will die.
你谋杀了我父亲
You murdered my father.
他自己选择的命运
He chose his own fate.
你也选择了你的
And you have chosen yours.
我们会战斗
We will fight.
你们会死
And you will die.
就这么定了
So be it.
大帝？
King?
海盗公会的 如杰克所说
Of the Brethren Court. Courtesy of Jack.
也许他真的知道自己想要什么
Maybe he really does know what he's doing.
漂亮！
Bravo!
你成功登上了飞翔荷兰人号 正如计划的那样
You've successfully arrived aboard the Dutchman as per the overall scheme.
- 你看 - 是的 帽子 伙计
- Look - Oh, yes. Chapeau, mate.
除去被关在牢里这部分 好像有点出乎意料
Except for this sojourn in the brig, it's utter clockwork.
走开
Go away.
- 什么？回到魔狱去？- 不能没有你 杰克
- What, back to the Locker? - Not without you, Jackie.
扎心脏
Stab the heart.
作为荷兰人号的船长永生不死
Live forever as captain of the Flying Dutchman.
当然了
Then again…
如果你在牢里
…if you're in the brig…
谁应该扎心脏
…who's to stab the heart?
现在离不死之身 好像有点远
Does seem to put immortality a bit out of reach.
哦！花生
Peanut.
我们要让黑珍珠号 作为旗舰领头攻击
We'll need to use the Black Pearl as a flagship to lead the attack.
- 我们要嘛？- 好吧 鱼女士 来吧
- Oh, will we now? - All right, Mrs. Fish. Come on.
巴布萨 你不能释放她
Barbossa, you can't release her.
我们要给杰克一个机会
We need to give Jack a chance.
我很抱歉 陛下 我的命运 不在我自己手中已经太久了
Apologies, Your Majesty. Too long my fate has not been in me own hands.
再也不会了
No longer.
敌人
The enemy…
选择了毁灭
…has opted for oblivion.
让舰队准备好
Ready the fleet.
- 各就各位！- 各就各位！
- To your stations. - To your stations.
要些仪式咒语什么的嘛？
Be there some manner of rite or incantation?
是
Aye.
物件全凑齐 好了
The items brought together, done.
烧掉物件
Items to be burned…
然后有人必须说
…and someone must speak the words:
「科莉布索 我把你从躯体里释放出来」
"Calypso, I release you from your human bonds."
就这样了？
Is that it?
要用对爱人讲话的口吻
'Tis said it must be spoken as if to a lover.
科莉布索 我把你从躯体里释放出来
Calypso, I release you from your human bonds!
- 就这样了？- 不不 他说的不对
- Is that it? - No, no, no. He didn't say it right.
他没有…
He didn't…
你 你要亲切点
You have to say it right.
科莉布索
Calypso…
我把你从躯体里释放出来
…I release you from your human bonds.
提亚·朵玛
Tia Dalma.
科莉布索
Calypso.
海盗公会禁锢你的时候 是谁告诉他们这么做的
When the Brethren Court imprisoned you, who was it that told them how?
- 是谁背叛了你 - 说出来
- Who was it that betrayed you? - Name him.
戴维·琼斯
Davy Jones.
这就是了！这就是了！
This is it! This is it!
科莉布索
Calypso!
我作为仆人跪在你面前 虔卑而懊悔
I come before you as but a servant, humble and contrite.
我完成了我的誓约 我现在请求你的帮助
I have fulfilled me vow and now ask your favor.
放过我 我的船和我船员
Spare meself, me ship, me crew…
将你的愤怒发泄于那些 敢于自命为你的主人
…but unleash your fury upon those who dare pretend themselves your masters…
或我的主人的人
…or mine.
就这样了？
Is that it?
她一点忙都没帮
Why, she's no help at all.
现在怎么办？
What now?
什么也不干
Nothing.
最后的希望也落空了
Our final hope has failed us.
- 还没完 - 战斗还在前头
- It's not over. - There's still a fight to be had.
我们要对付整个舰队 还有荷兰人号 没希望了
We've an armada against us, and with the Dutchman, there's no chance.
傻人或许有傻福
There's only a fool's chance.
复仇也救不回你父亲 斯旺小姐
Revenge won't bring your father back, Miss Swann,
我不打算为此送命
and it's not something I'm intending to die for.
你说得没错
You're right.
那我们为何送命？
Then what shall we die for?
你们给我听着
You will listen to me.
听着！
Listen!
海盗们还在看着我们 等着黑珍珠号领队
The Brethren will still be looking here to us, to the Black Pearl, to lead.
他们会看到什么？
And what will they see?
惊恐的鼠辈？被弃的破船？不！
Frightened bilge rats aboard a derelict ship? No.
不 他们会看到自由的人和自由！
No, they will see free men and freedom!
敌人会听见我们的炮声
And what the enemy will see is the flash of our cannons.
听见我们拔剑出鞘 看到我们的气势
They will hear the ring of our swords, and they will know what we can do.
以我们额头上的汗水
By the sweat of our brows,
我们脊背的力量
and the strength of our backs…
和我们心中的勇气
…and the courage of our hearts.
先生们
Gentlemen…
升起旗帜
…hoist the colors.
Hoist the colors.
- 升起旗帜 - 升起旗帜！
- Hoist the colors. - Hoist the colors!
对
Aye.
伙计们 风向对我们有利
The wind's on our side, boys. That's all we need!
升起旗帜
Hoist the colors!
伙计们 风向对我们有利
We have a favorable wind, sir.
如此甚好
Oh, so we do.
通知琼斯 不留活口
Signal Jones to give no quarter.
那会给他这一天增加亮点
That should brighten his day.
武器就位！我们不留活口
To arms! We give no quarter!
科莉布索！
Calypso.
你注意到没 这么多事 现在又下雨了？
Have you noticed, on top of everything, it's raining?
这是个坏兆头
That's a bad sign.
掌住绞盘 用力 加把劲
Man the capstan. Raise the main topyard. Keep that powder dry.
大漩涡
Maelstrom!
巴布萨船长！
Captain Barbossa!
我们要你去掌舵
We need you at the helm.
是 没错
Aye, that be true.
升起帆桁 你们这些 蠢货吊猿人
Brace up yards, you cack-handed deck apes.
要死也死得痛快
Dying is the day won'th living for.
转向！
Veer off!
她无法消灭我们！
She'll not harm us.
全力驶入深渊
Full-bore and into the abyss.
你疯了？
Are you mad?
哈 你怕湿吗？
Ha! You afraid to get wet?
它在往船艉靠近
She's on our stern and gaining.
掉头迎风前进 不要惧怕！
More speed! Haul your wind and hold your water.
放下火炮！
Bow cannons!
开炮！
Blow the cannons!
把船开出去 否则它会压倒我们
Take us out or they'll overbear us.
不 再进深些 我们会切入较快的水流
Nay. Further in. We'll cut across to faster waters.
准备接舷
Prepare to broadside.
准备火炮 帮帮忙
Captain the guns. Bear a hand.
鼓起勇气 随时待发
Muster your courage, men. At the ready.
象幼兽一样思考 象幼兽一样思考 象幼兽一样思考
Think like the whelp. Think like the whelp. Think like the whelp.
铰链 铰链
Hinges. Hinges.
象幼兽一样思考
Think like the whelp.
半桶铰链
Half-barrel hinges.
杠杆
Leverage.
祝我好运吧 我们需要好运
Wish us luck, boys. We'll need it.
- 我已经开始想他了 - 他好有魅力 是不是
- I miss him already. - He is quite charming, isn't he?
谁也别动
Nobody move.
我的脑子掉出来了
I dropped me brain.
封舱！
Batten down the hatches!
推出火炮
Stand to your guns.
船中炮手 瞄准
Midship cannoneers, sight the masts.
主炮就绪！
Main battery at the ready!
稳住！等到船舷对齐
Hold there! Wait till we're board-and-board.
开火！
Fire!
- 开火！- 开火！全部开火！
- Fire! - Fire! Fire all!
开火！
Fire!
加油 大伙们
Come on, men.
现在转向已经太晚了 船员们
It be too late to alter course now, mateys.
别动！否则我们会开火！
Halt there or we'll shoot.
说得好
Good one.
我只是来拿我的东西
I just come to get me effects.
虽然你们的行为值得尊敬 但为何你们要待在这里？
Admirable though it may be, why are you here when you could be elsewhere?
必须有人看管宝箱
Someone has to stay and guard the chest.
没错 最近这船上的军纪越来越涣散了
There's no question, there's a breakdown in military discipline on this vessel.
都怪那些鱼人
I blame the fish people.
噢 你的意思是 鱼人本性就一定散漫
Oh, so fish people, by dint of being fish people,
不象那些非鱼人？
automatically aren't as disciplined as non-fish people?
我只是说 他们做出了贡献
Seems contributory, is all I'm suggesting.
没错 如果没有那些鱼人 根本就不用看管宝箱
It's true, if there were no fish people, there'd be no need to guard the chest.
而且如果没有宝箱 我们也不用看管了
And if there were no chest we wouldn't need to be here to guard it.
准备登船！
Prepare to board!
寻找掩护！
Cover!
不！
No!
看哪 孩子们 一只迷途之鸟
Lookee here, boys. A lost bird.
一只从未学会飞行的雏鸟
A lost bird that never learned to fly.
这是我的遗憾
To my great regret.
但是…
But…
学习从来不嫌晚 对吧
…never too late to learn, eh?
箱子…拿来
The chest, hand it over.
我可以释放你 还你自由 老兄
I can set you free, mate.
我很久前就放弃自由了
My freedOm WaS fOrfeit IOng agO.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
现在求婚不妥吧
I don't think now's the best time.
这恐怕是我最后的机会了
Now may be the only time.
我爱你
I love you.
我主意已定 你呢？
I've made my choice. What's yours?
巴布萨
Barbossa.
帮我们证婚
Marry us.
我现在有点忙！
I'm a little busy at the moment.
巴布萨 快
Barbossa, now.
那好吧
Fine, then.
亲爱的各位 我们今天聚集在这里
Dearly beloved, we be gathered here today…
把你喉咙钉到桅杆上 你个杂种
To nail your gizzards to the mast, you poxy cur.
伊丽莎白·斯旺 你愿意接受我成为你的丈夫吗？
Elizabeth Swann, do you take me to be your husband?
- 我愿意 - 棒极了
- I do. - Great.
威尔·特纳…你愿意…
Will Turner, do you take me…
娶我为妻
…to be your wife…
不论生病或健康
…in sickness and in health…
健康的可能性比较小
…with health being the less likely?
我愿意
I do.
以船长的身分 我现在宣布你们…
As captain, I now pronounce you…
你们可以亲吻…
You may kiss…
快亲吧！
Just kiss.
别拿了
Leave it.
你没钥匙的话也没用
You can do nothing without the key.
我已经有钥匙了
I already have the key.
你才没有
No, you don't.
噢 那把钥匙
Oh, that key.
不！
No!
这是我的枪
Oi. My pistol.
特钠
Turner.
发射！
Fire!
谢了 杰克
Thank you, Jack.
停下！是我
Stop! Lt's me.
是威尔 你儿子呀
It's Will. Your son.
哈！
Ha!
去呀！
Go!
女海盗！我也不会手下留情的
Harridan! You'll see no mercy from me.
所以我才带了这个
That's why I brought this.
我不会杀你的 我答应过你
I'm not going to kill you. I made you a promise.
没打中
Missed.
你是否忘记了？我是没心脏的可怜人
Did you forget? I'm a heartless wretch.
爱
Ah. Love.
可怕的牵绊
A dreadful bond.
但却也容易切割
And yet, so easily severed.
告诉我 威廉·特纳 你怕死吗？
Tell me, William Turner, do you fear death?
你呢？
Do you?
真是美妙的结合 掌中同时把握着爱与死
Heady tonic, holding life and death in the palm of one's hand.
你真残忍 杰克·斯派洛
You're a cruel man, Jack Sparrow.
是否残忍要看个人出发点
Cruel is a matter of perspective.
是吗？
Is it?
威尔？
Will?
看着我 清醒点 你会没事的
Look at me! Stay with me! You're all right.
威廉？
William?
我儿
My son.
威尔 看着我 看着我
Will? Will? Look at me. Look at me!
我不会让你阻止我的判决
You will not forestall my judgment.
科莉布索
Calypso.
她要把我们拉下去了！把两条船分开 不然大家都下地狱
She's taking us down! Make quick or it's the Locker for us all!
不
No.
不！不！
No, no.
不
No!
船员的一份子 船的一部份
Part of the crew. Part of the ship, part of the crew.
Part of the ship, part of the crew.
别离开我！
Don't leave me.
别离开我！不！
Don't. No!
我不会离开你的
I won't leave you.
荷兰人号必须要有一个船长
The Dutchman must have a captain.
抓好
Hold on.
谢天谢地 杰克
Thank goodness, Jack.
敌方舰队还在那里 「努力号」快速地朝右舷而来
The armada's still out there. The Endeavor's coming up hard to starboard,
是时候发扬海盗的 最古老 最荣耀的传统了
and I think it's time we embrace that oldest and noblest of pirate traditions.
我一向不尊照传统
Never actually been one for tradition.
升帆 转舵 下锚
Close haul her. Luff the sails and lay her in irons.
别听他的 否则我们会成瓮中之鳖
Belay that, or we'll be a sitting duck.
别听他那句「别听他的」
Belay that "belay that."
- 但船长 - 别听他的
- But the arma… - Belay.
- 我们的努… - 闭嘴
- The Endeav… - Stow. Shut it.
他们在等什么？
What are they waiting for?
他期望我们履行我们的合约
He expects us to honor our agreement.
准备好枪和炮门
Ready guns and gun ports.
我并非针对你 杰克 只不过这是桩好交易
It's nothing personal, Jack. It's just good business.
啊 她还健在
Ah, she survived.
- 把炮准备好 - 把炮准备好
- Ready on the guns. - Guns ready.
升帆！
Full canvas.
Aye, full canvas.
请下令 长官
Orders, sir.
长官！
Sir!
船长
Cap'n.
- 开火 - 开火！
- Fire. - Fire!
- 开火！- 开火！
- Fire! - Fire!
全体开火！
Fire, all!
请下令 长官
Orders? Orders, sir?
长官 请下令
Sir, what do you command?
这只是…
Lt's just…
只不过是桩好交易
…good business.
弃船！
Abandon ship!
- 弃船！- 全体人员 弃船！
- Abandon ship! - All hands, abandon ship!
他们撤退了！
They're turning away!
一帆风顺
Wind in your sails.
吓老子
Shiver me timbers.
特纳船长！
Captain Turner!
- 吉伯斯先生 - 船长？
- Mr. Gibbs. - Cap'n?
- 你愿意的话 可以丢我的帽子 - 好的 船长
- You may throw my hat if you like. - Aye, aye, cap'n.
万岁！
Hooray!
去拿回来
Now go and get it.
请下令 长官
Orders, sir?
你已经不被荷兰人号束缚了 你自由了
You're no longer bound to the Dutchman. You're free.
是的
Aye.
这是好事 但是…
That's a fine thing, but…
我认为我还有一样债未还
…by my reckoning, I still have a debt that has to be paid.
如果你容许的话
If you'll have me.
去掌舵吧
On the wheel, then, Mr. Turner.
是的 特纳船长
Aye, Captain Turner.
这艘船有了新的使命
This ship has a purpose again.
我们要前往的地方
And where we are bound…
她不能跟来
…she cannot come.
一天上岸
One day ashore.
十年航海
Ten years at sea.
那是非常沉重的代价
That's a steep price for what's been done.
那要看上岸那天值不值得
Depends on the one day.
您的座驾准备好了 殿下
Your chariot awaits, Your Highness.
船桨在里面
The oars are inside.
特纳夫人
Mrs. Turner.
再见 妞妞
Goodbye, poppet.
杰克
Jack.
我们之间永远不会有结果的
It would never have worked out between us.
你继续说服你自己吧 亲爱的
Keep telling yourself that, darling.
一次就够了
Once was quite enough.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我需要另一只
I'm going to need the other one.
太阳快下山了
It's nearly sunset.
它一直都属于你
Lt's always belonged to you.
你能好好保管它吗？
Will you keep it safe?
当然
Yes.
是的
威尔！
Will!
看着海平面等我回来
Keep a weather eye on the horizon.
虽然它倾向左舷
Granted it tends to list to port, and has been, on occasion,
而且有时会吓坏女人
known to frighten young women.
但我保证 你们不会失望的
But I promise you, you will not be disappointed.
就是那个？
Is that it?
黑珍珠？
The Black Pearl.
不大呀
It's not very big.
甜心 那是条小艇
Love, that is a dinghy.
我的船非常宏伟、凶猛、巨大…而且…
My vessel is magnificent and fierce and huge-ish and…
不见了 怎么会不见了？
…gone. Why is it gone?
是不是那艘？
Is that it there?
是的 正是那艘
Yes, there it is.
为什么会在那里？
Why is it there?
近看的话大很多
Lt's much larger up close.
杰克 你答应带我们去兜风的
Jack, you promised to take us for a ride.
- 我本来应该是第一个上船的 - 什么 你？
- I was to be given the first ride. - What? You?
- 他不是这么说的 - 我绝不！
- Not what he said. - I never!
吉伯斯先生 为什么我的船不见了？
Mr. Gibbs? Any particular reason why my ship is gone?
船？我们在船上
The ship? We're on the ship.
杰克 船不见了！
Jack! The ship's gone!
真的？
Really?
女士们 能不能闭嘴？
Ladies! Will you please shut it?
听我说 是的 我骗了你们
Listen to me. Yes, I lied to you.
不 我不爱你们
No, I don't love you.
当然让你看起来很胖 我没去过布鲁塞尔
Of course it makes you look fat. I've never been to Brussels.
发音是「极…坏…的」
It is pronounced "egregious."
我从未见过比萨罗 但我很喜欢他的派
By the way, no, I've never actually met Pizarro, but I love his pies.
这些都不重要 因为我的船
And all of this pales to utter insignificance.
又一次不见了 懂了？
in light of the fact that my ship is once again gone. Savvy?
- 拿走你能拿的 - 一点都不放过
- Take what you can. - Give nothing back.
告诉我 女士们 你们对海龟了解多少？
Tell me, ladies, what do you know of sea turtles?
海龟？
Sea turtles?
我跟你说说激动人心的船长故事…
Let me tell you the amazing story of Cap…
全都上梯绳
All men up the ratlines.
全都上梯绳！
All men up the ratlines!
你想尝尝这个吗？
Oh, you want a taste of this?
好孩子 你真是个乖孩子
Oh, that's a good boy! You're Daddy's boy.
哦 是的 你是好孩子
Oh, yes, you are. Oh, yes, you are.
长官？
Sir?
有些船员觉得不该
Some of the men don't feel entirely settled.
- 丢下杰克 - 又一次
- about leaving Captain Jack behind. - Again.
- 又一次 - 是嘛
- Again. - Is that so?
如果你能让我们看看你所说的宝藏
Lt would make us feel a whole lot better regarding our fortunes.
我们会安心许多
if we could see that item you told us about.
- 在航海图上的方位 - 是的
- On the charts. - Aye.
让我们亲眼看看
With our own eyes.
也可以帮助我们减轻罪恶感
To help put an ease to our burden of guilt, so to speak.
啊
Ah.
睁大眼好好瞧瞧吧 伙计们
Feast your eyes upon this, mateys.
长生不老不是只有一种方法
There's more than one way to live forever.
男士们 见识一下不老泉
Gents, I give you the Fountain of Youth.
斯派洛
Sparrow.
∮ 呦吼 呦吼 我的海盗生涯 ∮
∮ Yo ho, yo ho A pirate's life for me ∮
我们是恶魔 是害群之马 地地道道的大坏蛋
We're devils and black sheep Really bad eggs.
∮ 喝干这杯 无忧也无愁 ∮
∮ Drink up, me hearties Yo ho ∮
∮ 呦吼 呦吼 我的海盗生涯 ∮
∮ Yo ho, yo ho A pirate's life for me ∮
∮ 我们杀人越货 我们无恶不作 ∮
∮ We pillage, we plunder We rifle and loot ∮
∮ 喝干这杯 无忧也无愁 ∮
∮ Drink up, me hearties Yo ho ∮
∮ 我们绑架掳掠 我们无恶不作 ∮
∮ We kidnap and ravage And don't give a hoot ∮
∮ 喝干这杯 无忧也无愁 ∮
∮ Drink up, me hearties Yo ho ∮
∮ 呦吼 呦吼 我的海盗生涯 ∮
∮ Yo ho, yo ho A pirate's life for me ∮